0300 HOURS OPERATION ROOM
（時刻：0300，作戰室）
Okonogi, status report.
小此木，報告現況
Yes, ma'am.
是
Evacuation of the surrounding area began at 0245.
周邊居民已於0245開始避難
Emergency Kaiju alert.
緊急怪獸警報…
The epicenter is located in Sagamihara.
震央位於相模原
Citizens in the surrounding area are asked to follow JGSDF orders and evacuate.
周邊居民請遵循自衛隊的引導進行避難
I repeat...
重複一次…
Why Sagamihara?
為什麼是相模原啊？
Is the Defense Force here yet?
防衛隊還沒來嗎？
Mommy, I gotta go to the bathroom!
媽媽，我想去廁所
Stay calm, everyone!
大家別慌張
The next buses will arrive soon! Stay calm and evacuate!
下台車馬上就到了，請保持冷靜
KAIJU EVACUATION
（怪獸避難）
There's room on the buses for everyone!
避難車輛非常充足
Are we working with the JGSDF?
與自衛隊合作的狀況呢？
A JGSDF artillery regiment command post
利旺夢樂城的停車場
is being constructed at the Leon Mall parking lot.
正在設置自衛隊特科連隊指揮處
Deploying FO.
部屬前進觀測員
Observation post constructed.
觀測所設置完畢
Sitrep on the evacuation progress.
請提供避難的進度報告
And the Honju?
主獸狀況如何？
It first appeared at Kannawa Fault
出現在神繩斷層之後
and moved underground while growing larger.
牠就在地底成長並同時移動
It's believed to have surfaced because it's entered its breeding phase.
應該是進入了增殖期，才會在地面現身
The appearance of the Honju has been followed by
受到主獸出現的影響
the appearance of a large number of Yoju.
也出現了大量的餘獸
Come on, how many of these things are there?
真誇張，到底有多少隻啊？
Fortunately, the neutralization area isn't that far away.
幸好離討伐區域並不遠
If we want to minimize damage to the surrounding area,
如果想減少周邊區域的損害
our best option is to defeat the Honju in the central Sector Bravo.
討伐區域內側的B地區 最適合用來擊倒主獸
I'll handle the Honju.
主獸由我來負責
Sector Echo will serve as the sniper point.
狙擊點設在E地區
We'll be able to target the enemies from alongside Highway 16.
在這裡就能沿著東京環狀線鎖定敵方
This operation will be designated as
本次作戰命名為「相模原討伐作戰」
Best of luck to all of you.
祝各位戰鬥順利
KAIJU EXCLUSIVE LANE
（怪獸專用道路）
Y'all feeling ready?
做好覺悟了嗎？
It's time to go Kaiju hunting.
討伐怪獸的時候到了
Kaiju No. 8.
怪獸8號
I still can't believe it...
雖然我還是覺得難以置信
But don't disappoint me, Kafka Hibino.
你可別讓我失望喔，日比野卡夫卡
Vice-Captain, Senpai's about to throw up!
副隊長，前輩好像快吐了！
Sorry! I was so nervous, I ate too much food!
抱歉，我太緊張就吃多了
Normally, you get too nervous to eat!
正常人應該是會沒食欲吧！
Open a window! Now!
快打開窗戶！
If you throw up, I'll kill you!
你敢吐，我就殺了你！
What's wrong with you, old dude?
大叔你搞什麼啊？
Please don't kill me!
拜託饒命啊
0400 HOURS JGSDF COMMAND POST 304 LEON MALL SAGAMIHARA PARKING LOT
（時刻：0400，自衛隊304指揮處） （利旺夢樂城相模原店停車場）
0400 HOURS LEON MALL SAGAMIHARA EVACUATION AREA
（同時間，利旺夢樂城相模原店避難所）
0400 HOURS JAPANESE GROUND SELF-DEFENSE FORCES ANTI-KAIJU ARTILLERY BATTALION
（同時間，陸上自衛隊對怪獸特科大隊）
0400 HOURS SECTOR E
（同時間，E地區）
So this is the neutralization area.
這裡就是討伐區域
And that's...
那就是…
...the Honju for this mission!
這次的主獸
EPISODE 6: SAGAMIHARA NEUTRALIZATION OPERATION AT DAYBREAK
（第6集：黎明的相模原討伐作戰）
I'll brief you on the operation.
現在宣布作戰計劃
Captain Ashiro's unit will handle the Honju.
主獸由亞白隊長帶隊負責
The problem is that it's creating a ton of Yoju.
問題是不停出現的無數餘獸
This neutralization area is kept deliberately clear
這個討伐區域並未設置
of important infrastructure and critical transportation routes.
重要機關和主要交通網
Your job will be to make sure no Yoju escape from this area.
（F地區，斑鳩小隊）
It's an important job that determines how much damage is dealt,
任務達成與否將大幅影響 受害範圍、重建費用
how much it costs to rebuild from that damage, and how long it'll take.
以及重建的時間，這是一項很重要的工作
Of course, any platoon with new recruits will be placed at the very rear.
當然了，有新人的小隊會配置在最後方
But that also means...
換句話說
you're our last line of defense.
這也代表你們就是最後防線
Anybody got questions?
有什麼疑問嗎？
Good.
很好
No matter how good your scores are during training,
在訓練場就算拿到再高的成績
that won't save a single life.
也無法拯救任何生命
It's time, recruits. Show me what you can do on the battlefield.
在戰場上發揮實力吧，小菜鳥們
All right, let's go!
好，我們上！
Have fun out there, guys.
那就拜託大家囉
This is the JGSDF Artillery Regiment Command Post.
這裡是自衛隊特科連隊指揮處
Civilian evacuation and command post construction complete.
居民避難完畢，觀測所也設置完成
Message received. Thank you for your cooperation.
瞭解，感謝各位的協助
All platoons and all JGSDF forces are ready to go.
各小隊與自衛隊皆準備完畢
Eight minutes until Captain Ashiro reaches her position.
距離亞白隊長抵達配置地點，還有8分鐘
It's time, right, Senpai?
時候終於到了，前輩
Yeah.
是啊
During this mission, I have to prove I can do the job.
我得趁這次機會好好表現
You're never gonna be a full officer at this rate.
再這樣下去，你無法成為正式隊員喔
You'll be fired in three months.
三個月後就會被開除了
I won't get another shot.
我已經無路可退了
Nervousness. Panic.
緊張、焦慮
I'm feeling all kinds of pressure.
各種壓力排山倒海而來
But for some reason...
但是，不知為何…
I'm also incredibly excited!
我覺得好興奮啊
Yeah, that's right.
也是啦
This is the job you've always wanted.
畢竟這是你夢寐以求的工作
Senpai.
前輩
Let's make sure our first mission is a big success!
我們絕對要讓第一個任務成功
Right!
好
Yoju sighted in Sector Echo!
E地區發現餘獸入侵
They're here.
牠們來了
Time to go, Kikoru.
琪歌露，我們走
Why are you telling me what to do?
誰准你發號施令了啊？
Don't die out there, Ichikawa!
市川，你可別死掉喔
You too, Senpai!
前輩你也是
Okay!
看我的
Time to make my first mission a big success!
我要成功完成第一個任務！
Captain Ashiro has reached the sniper point.
亞白隊長已抵達狙擊點
Please lure the Honju to Sector Bravo and provide fire support.
請將主獸引誘至B地區，並提供火力支援
Roger that.
瞭解
JGSDF Artillery Regiment Command Post,
這裡是自衛隊特科連隊指揮處
now initiating fire support for the Defense Force.
開始對防衛隊提供火力支援
Time for your big debut.
出道戰總算開始了
Start by showing your superiors just how damn good you really are.
先讓前輩們嚇個目瞪口呆吧
It's begun.
開始了
But it's not like the exam.
但這跟測驗時不一樣
I feel strangely calm...
我莫名地鎮定
I can tell the suit is helping me.
我感受得到戰鬥服正在回應我
Unleashing combat power!
戰力解放！
You're too far out in front!
你衝太前面了吧！
Your combat power is 1%, so stay in the rear!
戰鬥力只有1%的人就給我退到後面去
Sheesh.
真是的
Why do we have to babysit the new kids?
為什麼我們還得保護新人啊？
Can't you guys just go someplace you won't get in our way and watch?
你們至少別礙事，乖乖在一旁觀摩吧
Listen up!
聽好了
We don't know the enemy's vulnerable points.
我們還不清楚敵方的弱點
Play it safe until we get info from the guys on the front line.
在前線隊員提供情報之前要謹慎
Roger that.
瞭解
I'll play it safe and blast anything that could be a weak point.
我會謹慎地擊破所有疑似弱點的部位
What the hell?
這是怎麼回事？
That's not the kind of firepower you see from a rookie!
這不像入隊一兩個月該有的威力
So that's the power of Kikoru Shinomiya.
這就是四之宮琪歌露的實力嗎？
Kikoru...
琪歌露
Nice!
幹得好
What else would you expect from me?
這還用你說嗎？你以為我是誰啊
Abnormal vital signs detected.
生命徵象出現異常
Rapid increase in heart rate.
心跳急速上升
You don't need to tell me that!
這種事不用報告啦！
SECTOR F
（F地區）
There we go!
好，已攻破兩隻腳了，給予最後一擊
Well done, Furuhashi!
幹得好，古橋
There we go!
好耶
You see that, Reno?
雷諾，你看見沒？
Did you do that by yourself?
你獨自解決那隻嗎？
Yes.
對
I swapped out the burst rounds in my gun for freeze rounds.
我試著把彈藥從炸裂彈換成凍結彈
I think it's a better fit for my style.
這樣好像比較適合我
I can slow down the enemy while I fight.
能在戰鬥時讓敵方動作變遲緩
I think, once I get the hang of this, I'll be even better at hunting Kaiju.
等我掌握訣竅後 應該可以變得更會狩獵怪獸
I'm not there yet.
還不夠
I need to get stronger.
我需要變得更強才行
So Senpai won't have to transform!
我得強到讓前輩不用變身
SECTOR J
（J地區）
They're so damn speedy!
動作真迅速
Wh-What's the deal with this year's recruits?
今年的新人是怎麼回事啊？
Platoon Leader Nakanoshima!
中之島小隊長
What's going on with those guys? I'm losing my self-confidence here!
那些人太誇張了吧？我快喪失自信了
I've taken down six already.
我已經解決六隻了
You're going a little slow, aren't you, Haruichi?
你的速度有點慢呢，陽一
Right, right.
對啦
Don't forget that you only got four of those six 'cause I backed you up.
你可別忘了我有幫忙你解決其中四隻
One's a wild child. One's the clean-cut type.
一個是狂野型，一個是清新型
COUGAR MODE
（肉食系）
Yeah, it's a good year.
今年的確是大豐收呢
You're talking about their looks?
你是在說長相嗎？
Vice-Captain Hoshina told me there are a few really good ones.
我聽保科副隊長說有幾個人特別優秀
But that's not all.
但看來不只如此呢
The average unleashed combat power of the new recruits is higher than in most years.
今年新人的平均解放戰力比往年還高
The guys at the top are motivating the others to do better.
看來是受到頂尖隊員的影響 讓整體水準提升了
Number eight!
第八隻
That was totally my kill!
剛才這隻是我的功勞吧
Our observation teams have verified that Sector Juliet is clear of Yoju.
觀測組回報J地區周邊確認沒有餘獸
All Yoju have been defeated.
餘獸已被殲滅
The kill reports keep coming.
打倒怪獸的報告陸續傳來
They're all amazing!
大家都好厲害
Ikaruga Platoon will advance, with Ichikawa and Furuhashi at the forefront.
斑鳩小隊
Ichikawa and Iharu, too?
市川跟伊春也是？
This is no good.
不行
Everyone's working so hard, and I'm just slowing them down.
大家都這麼努力，我卻只會扯後腿
Isn't there anything I can do?
就沒有什麼我能做的事了嗎？
Wait, didn't he just say...
對了，剛才…
Listen up!
聽好了
We don't know the enemy's vulnerable points.
我們還不清楚敵人的弱點
Play it safe until we get info from the guys on the front line.
在前線隊員提供情報之前要謹慎
I'll fight with my own weapons!
我要用我自己的武器戰鬥
Senpai, look!
前輩，你看那邊
What the hell's he doing?
他在幹嘛啊？
Wow, even with just 1%,
就算只有1%
the suit makes it easy to dismantle their bodies.
有了戰鬥服的幫忙，解體變得好輕鬆
If they could mass-produce these things,
要是這可以量產的話
it'd be nice if they gave some to the cleanup industry.
真希望他們也可以賣給解體業者
This is a pretty standard structure for fungal-type Kaiju,
這是菌類系怪獸常見的構造
but the core's not where it usually is.
但核心並不在原本應該的位置
Where is it?
會在哪裡？
If it's not here, then maybe over there?
如果不是這裡，會是這邊嗎？
Wait a second...
這是？
Vice-Captain Hoshina, I've located the Yoju core.
保科副隊長，我知道餘獸的核心在哪裡了
What?
什麼？
It's at the base of the neck,
是在頸根部
but there are hard, fibrous muscles on top of it that serve as its backbone.
但它在背脊的硬纖維肌下面
Officers with weaker attack power might need to hit them from the sides.
所以攻擊力較低的隊員 不從側面攻擊可能無法擊穿核心
And there's one more thing. This one's important.
還有一件事，這點很重要
The Yoju have reproductive organs too.
餘獸也有增殖器官
The white, bumpy organs near their rears.
就是臀部附近，白色凹凸狀的器官
If we don't destroy those organs, their corpses might spawn new Yoju.
不破壞的話 餘獸屍體可能會生出新的餘獸
Kafka.
卡夫卡
That's some damn fine work.
幹得漂亮
Okonogi-chan, share that news with the rest of the team.
小此木，把這個情報轉達給全體隊員
Roger that.
瞭解
Sharing information on Yoju core and reproductive organs with all officers.
正在分享餘獸核心和增殖器官的資料
I'm sure you picked up some of that at your last job,
雖然是來自上一份工作的經驗
but I guess your studying really paid off.
但這也是你平時認真學習的成果
Well done.
做得好
I helped the Defense Force!
我對防衛隊有所貢獻了
I'll go neutralize all the corpses of the defeated Yoju!
我現在就去破壞所有在地上的屍體
I'll do everything I can, no matter what it is,
只要我能做到的，我都會盡我所能
until I reach Mina's side!
直到自己站在米娜身邊為止
What?
怎麼了？
Looks like they've started for the day too.
看來另一邊也開戰了
Honju has reached the designated combat initiation point.
主獸抵達預定接戰地點
JGSDF ground and air forces are requested to withdraw.
請求自衛隊陸上及航空隊撤離
The Defense Force will initiate an attack on the Honju's legs.
防衛隊開始攻擊主獸腳部
Please keep it pinned down as long as you can.
請盡可能阻止主獸移動
Target sighted.
鎖定目標
Compensation for Coriolis force, gravitational force complete.
科氏力、重力效果補正完畢
No additional targets in area.
周邊無狙擊的威脅對象
One round loaded and ready to fire.
第一彈裝填完畢
Roger.
瞭解
All conditions met for firing to commence.
所有狙擊條件均已符合
You are cleared to fire.
開始射擊
Let's see who can be a cooler Defense Force officer!
我們來比賽，看誰能成為帥氣的防衛隊員
Kafka-kun...
卡夫卡
This is who I am right now.
這就是現在的我
Unleashed combat power, 96%.
解放戰力96%
Watch this one closely, Kafka.
卡夫卡，看仔細了
Fire.
射擊
That's the power of the person you're trying to stand beside.
這就是你希望能與其並肩作戰之人的力量
Second round loaded and ready to fire.
第二彈裝填完畢
Roger. You are cleared to fire.
瞭解，開始射擊
Honju vital signs have disappeared.
主獸的活體徵象消失
It's collapsing!
牠要倒下了
Third round loaded and ready to fire.
第三彈裝填完畢
R-Roger.
瞭解
You are cleared to fire.
開始射擊
The Honju has taken critical damage and has stopped moving entirely.
擊破主獸，已完全停止活動
That's the captain for you.
不愧是隊長
Fourth round loaded and ready to fire.
第四彈裝填完畢
Give the order.
請下令
R-Roger.
瞭解
Damn it!
可惡
It's totally different from when you look at it on TV or through binoculars!
這跟用電視或望遠鏡看到的根本不一樣
She's incredible!
她果然很不得了
Feel like giving up?
你萌生退意了嗎？
Standing by her side means matching that kind of strength.
想跟她並肩作戰 就代表需要具備與她同等的能力
And can you do that, Vice-Captain Hoshina?
保科副隊長你也有那種能耐嗎？
-Not a chance! -Not a chance?!
-我無法 -竟然無法？
My unleashed combat power isn't as good when it comes to the long-range guns,
我的長程狙擊武器的解放戰力很低
so I'm not as capable of taking down the big boys as she is.
在對付大型怪獸方面，我敵不過亞白隊長
But when it comes to the smaller and mid-sized enemies...
但對付小型和中型怪獸…
Vice-Captain! Behind you!
副隊長，你後面！
I think I'm a bit better than she is.
…我應該略勝她一籌
A katana?
刀？
It was so fast I couldn't see it at all!
迅速到我完全看不見
My family's been a clan of Kaiju-hunters since the days of the Muromachi period.
我的家族從室町時代起 就是怪獸討伐一族
I'm much better at this stuff.
所以我比較擅長用刀
A captain and vice-captain are the force's most powerful members.
隊長和副隊長等級，就是部隊最強的戰力
We each get special equipment tailored to our fighting styles.
所以會依個人特質配備專用裝備
Hoshina, the Honju's down.
保科，主獸已經解決了
Roger.
瞭解
That's enough chatting. The real show's about to start.
閒聊結束，好戲要開始囉
But she just said she took down the Honju...
可是她剛說打倒主獸了
I told you during the briefing.
我說過了吧？
The problem is the countless Yoju it creates.
問題在於會無數增殖的餘獸
We killed the Honju, but the Yoju are still alive inside its corpse...
就算打倒主獸，屍體裡還有殘留的餘獸
Just like I thought.
果然如事前所料
Here they come.
牠們來了
And are going to come swarming out.
最後會傾巢而出
All right, guys! We're wrapping up here.
好了，各位，來收尾吧
Once we're done cleaning up the riff-raff,
早早收拾牠們
we can all go home and have a yummy breakfast.
就能回去享用美味早餐了
Cleaning up the riff-raff? He makes it sound so easy.
收拾？說得好像很簡單
Wimpin' out already, recruits?
小菜鳥們已經累垮了嗎？
Looks like you need to work on your stamina!
你們的體力還要加強喔
All right, guys!
各位！
Let's show them that there's more to fighting than your unleashed combat power!
讓新人知道戰鬥並不是只靠解放戰力
Right!
是！
Hey, you two.
你們兩位
Platoon Leader Nakanoshima.
中之島小隊長？
You're free to rest and let the veterans do the work, you know.
剩下的就交給前輩 你們去休息也沒關係喔
What'll it be?
如何？
We'll fight, obviously!
-當然要去戰鬥！
DEPLOYED OFFICERS STATUS
（作戰配置隊員活動狀況）
The new recruits are tired.
新人都累了
Their unleashed combat power and endurance are both falling.
耐久力和解放戰力都有所下滑
It's a big neutralization to have for their first mission.
以第一個任務來說，這算是很棘手的討伐
But if they can make it through this, it'll take them to the next level.
但只要能撐過去，就有可能邁向更高境界
Most officers end their careers with
大部分隊員的解放戰力
unleashed combat power topping out at around 20% to 30%,
都停留在20%至30% 並以一般隊員的身分結束隊員生涯
but a very small number of them will overcome that wall and become captains.
只有極少數人能突破高牆 成長為隊長等級的人材
Right now, the only one of the new recruits
今年突破這道高牆的新人
to reach that level is Kikoru Shinomiya.
只有四之宮琪歌露
But there might be one more...
但還有另一個人…
I think Reno Ichikawa might be up for it as well.
我認為市川雷諾也有這個潛力
Damn it.
可惡
I spent five years in technical college training every day!
我在專科學校接受了五年的嚴格訓練
Why can't I keep up with him?
為什麼卻追不上他的腳步？
Iharu-kun.
伊春
I don't think there are any more Yoju here.
這裡應該已經沒有餘獸了
Yeah, looks like you're right.
嗯，看來是這樣沒錯
New Yoju entering Sector Foxtrot.
F地區發現餘獸入侵
They're here. Let's return to the front lines.
來了，我們返回戰場吧
Right.
好
Monster Sweeper Inc.?
Monster Sweeper公司？
What's one of the cleaners doing out here?
解體作業人員為什麼會在這裡？
Hey, you didn't hear the alarm?
喂，你沒聽到警報嗎？
The cleanup crew won't be needed until later.
現在還沒輪到解體業者出場
Aw, this one's no good either.
這傢伙也一樣
The reproductive organs I loaded them with have been destroyed.
事先放入的增殖器官被破壞了
How did they find out?
怎麼會被發現啊？
Maybe there's somebody on the force who knows all about Kaiju?
隊員裡有人很瞭解怪獸嗎？
You guys know anything?
你們知道些什麼嗎？